Guide to the Folio Club Records, 1927-2013 RL.10195
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Folio Club records
1927-2013
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Folio Club
RL.10195
3 Linear Feet
Durham's Folio Club was founded by Duke University faculty wives and other Duke-affiliated women in 1927. This collection includes the records of the Folio Club, including meeting minutes, programs, correspondence, and clippings related to the activities of the club and its members.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Historical note
The Folio Club was established by faculty wives at Duke University in the fall of 1927. Originally, the club consisted of 14 women who paid dues of 75 cents. Early meetings consisted of knitting, conversation, a book review, and tea. They evolved over time to adopt formal study of topics, ranging from art and history to music and political movements. Each member was responsible for either hosting or leading a program at least once per year. The club also raised money in support of local civic groups and organizations, including the Durham County Library, The Red Cross, hospitals and arts programs, and children's groups.
Provenance
The Folio Club Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1983, with additions in 2003 and 2015.
Collection Overview
The Folio Club Records include meeting minutes and notes from the foundation of the club through recent years, reflecting the evolution and development of the club from a small group of Duke faculty wives to a large club of women with affiliations throughout the Durham area. Also included are correspondence files, which consist largely of postcard invitations to club programs and letters from members nominating new women to join the group. Also included are several versions of the club's constitution; photographs, some with labels, of the club's members; a handwritten history of the club's first 50 years; and programs collected by the club historian dating from 1937 through 2012 (an incomplete run). The annual programs include membership directories and a schedule of club events, usually centered around a theme. Some are annotated by their former owners.
Book clubs (Discussion groups); Audiocassettes; Women -- North Carolina -- Durham -- Societies and clubs.; Women -- Societies and clubs -- North Carolina; Women -- Societies and clubs -- Archives.; Duke University. Faculty; Folio Club
- Records, 1927-2013
  - History of the Folio Club, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Constitutions, 1960s-2006 and undated (Box 1)
  - Finances, 1960s-2010s; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1970s-1990s and undated (Box 1)
  - Photograph (oversize panorama), 2011 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - News clippings about Folio members, 1980s-2000s (Box 1)
  - Member deaths and obituaries (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1950s-2010s; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Meeting minutes books and binders, 1928-2012; 8 folders (Box 2)
  - Meeting minutes binder pages, 2011-2013 (Box 3)
  - Annual program booklets, 1937-2012; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Reports and visual aids from various programs and meetings, 1980s-2000s (Box 3)
- Audiocassettes, 1987-1989; 1
  - A. Kathie Bryson on Anne Morrow Lindbergh; B. Phyllis Parker on Ruth Montgomery, 1987 October 1, 1987 November 5; 1
    - Original audiocassette (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL10195-CS-0001)
  - Virginia Johnston and Mary Jane Rivers on Robert Frost, 1987 December 3; 2
    - Original audiocassette (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL10195-CS-0002)
  - Snow Roberts on Edith Hamilton, 1988 January 8; 3
    - Original audiocassette (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL10195-CS-0003)
    - Audiocassette copy (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL10195-CS-0004)
  - Sue Beischer on Emily Dickinson, 1988 March 3; 4
    - Original audiocassette (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL10195-CS-0005)
  - A. Mary and Watts Hill, "Galapagos Islands"; B. Barbara Yowell on Pat Conroy, 1988 October 6, 1988 December 1; 5
    - Original audiocassette (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL10195-CS-0006)
  - Janet Stead on Margaret Wise Brown, 1989 January 5; 6
    - Original audiocassette (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL10195-CS-0007)
  - A. Karen Hauighurst on Robertson Davies; B. Mary Jane Rivers on Langston Hughes, 1989 February 2, 1989 March 2; 7
    - Original audiocassette (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL10195-CS-0008)
  - Margaret Haywood on Beryl Markham, 1989 April 7; 8
    - Original audiocassette (Box 4, Audio-cassette RL10195-CS-0009)